const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"What is the advantage of fingerprinting?","answers":[{"option":"No special training required","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all people","bool":false},{"option":"It is applicable for all age groups","bool":false},{"option":"It enables absolute identification of an individual","bool":true},{"option":"It does not require any special and expensive instruments","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Fat is stored in the body in what form?","answers":[{"option":"Fatty acids","bool":false},{"option":"Ghee","bool":false},{"option":"Wax","bool":false},{"option":"Triglycerides","bool":true},{"option":"Cholesterol","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A 23-year-old man presents with pain in his tooth. Upon inspection it is found that pain is in the joint between the tooth and its root. Which joint is this?","answers":[{"option":"Ball-and-socket","bool":false},{"option":"Synchondrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrous","bool":true},{"option":"Hyaline","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilaginous","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following descriptions of the anatomical position is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Squatting position, both arms by side, and both feet inverted","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms abducted, both feet together","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, face forward, arms by the side and flexed","bool":false},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms by the side, and both feet together","bool":true},{"option":"Standing straight, both arms by the side and feet everted","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following takes part in the regulation of gene expression?","answers":[{"option":"ssRNA","bool":false},{"option":"miRNA","bool":true},{"option":"rRNA","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"tRNA","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A dense connective tissue containing bundles of collagen fibers that run parallel to each other and have only fibroblast cells with flattened nuclei in between them. This tissue is present in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Tendon","bool":true},{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Ligament","bool":false},{"option":"Aponeurosis","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"In which of the following conditions does isosmotic volume contraction occur?","answers":[{"option":"Increased antidiuretic hormone (ADH) secretion","bool":false},{"option":"Increased absorption of salts from intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Diarrhea","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Excessive blood loss","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"What does vomiting lead to?","answers":[{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Hypoglycemia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypernatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hyperkalemia","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The teacher asks the student to stand in an anatomical position. Which of the following correctly defines his position?","answers":[{"option":"Face facing forward, standing erect, arms folded, palms facing forward","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards the teacher, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing teacher's side","bool":false},{"option":"Face towards the teacher, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing backwards","bool":false},{"option":"Face facing forward, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing forward","bool":true},{"option":"Face towards the feet, standing erect, arms adjacent to sides, palms facing backwards","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which term refers to the twisting of the foot in the inward direction?","answers":[{"option":"Eversion","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsiflexion","bool":false},{"option":"All of these","bool":false},{"option":"Plantarflexion","bool":false},{"option":"Inversion","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Okazaki fragments are formed on the ______ strands in the ______ direction.","answers":[{"option":"Lagging, 3'-5'","bool":false},{"option":"Both same","bool":false},{"option":"Leading, 3'-5'","bool":false},{"option":"Lagging, 5'-3'","bool":true},{"option":"Leading, 5'-3'","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which type of cell change occurs due to long-standing hypertension?","answers":[{"option":"Hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Atrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Dysplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy","bool":true},{"option":"Metaplasia","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"What is the hallmark of irreversible injury?","answers":[{"option":"Loss of proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular swelling","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of nucleus","bool":true},{"option":"Eosinophilia","bool":false},{"option":"Cellular blebbing","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"While performing an ultrasound, the physician cannot distinguish the embryo craniocaudally. This is most possibly due to the absence of which of the following events?","answers":[{"option":"Formation of trophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of notochord","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of syncytiotrophoblast","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of epiblast","bool":false},{"option":"Formation of primitive streak","bool":true}]},{"id":14,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A hypertensive patient is given an angiotensin-converting enzyme (ACE) inhibitor that works by lowering Vmax. What type of inhibition is most likely to be involved in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Non-competitive","bool":true},{"option":"Full agonist","bool":false},{"option":"Allosteric","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive","bool":false},{"option":"Partial agonist","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The World Health Organization (WHO) has given the concept of a healthy city. What is the primary objective of this action plan?","answers":[{"option":"Start income generation activities","bool":false},{"option":"Stimulate economic development dialogue","bool":false},{"option":"Improve health and quality of life of urban dwellers","bool":true},{"option":"Make people partners","bool":false},{"option":"Social support network","bool":false}]},{"id":16,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the bacterial cell shows the most antigenic variability?","answers":[{"option":"Spore","bool":false},{"option":"Peptidoglycan","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":true},{"option":"Slime","bool":false},{"option":"Lipid A of endotoxin","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A radiologist observes no line separating the epiphysis and diaphysis on an X-ray because of the complete fusion of bones. What is this joint at the epiphyseal plate called?","answers":[{"option":"Symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Synovial joint","bool":false},{"option":"Primary cartilaginous joint","bool":true},{"option":"Syndesmosis","bool":false},{"option":"Secondary cartilaginous joint","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Cerebrosides are composed of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Sphingosine, galactose, fatty acid, and ceramide","bool":true},{"option":"Sphingosine, ceramide, and phosphate","bool":false},{"option":"Fatty acids and ceramide only","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingosine, phosphate, and fatty acid","bool":false},{"option":"Ceramides only","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is not a component of the Graafian follicle?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary oocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Granulosa cells","bool":false},{"option":"Cumulus oophorus","bool":false},{"option":"Zona pellucida","bool":false},{"option":"Primary oocyte","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following structures contains keratin sulfate in abundance?","answers":[{"option":"Extracellular membrane","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Hepatocyte","bool":false},{"option":"Cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"Cornea","bool":true}]},{"id":21,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following types of cell junctions does not allow passage of extracellular fluid via the paracellular route?","answers":[{"option":"Desmosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Hemidesmosomes","bool":false},{"option":"Zonula occludens","bool":true},{"option":"Macula adherens","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following types of muscles is responsible for the dilation and constriction of blood vessels?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth muscle","bool":true},{"option":"Skeletal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Smooth and skeletal muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac and smooth muscle","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Tendons are classified as what type of connective tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Dense irregular connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Areolar connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Adipose tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Loose connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"Dense regular connective tissue","bool":true}]},{"id":24,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A woman presents with an injury to the pubic symphysis after a motorbike accident. The pubic symphysis is a secondary cartilaginous joint. Which of the following is not a characteristic of secondary cartilaginous joints?","answers":[{"option":"Lies in the midline of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Also called symphysis","bool":false},{"option":"Covered with synovial membrane","bool":true},{"option":"Slightly moveable joint","bool":false},{"option":"United by fibrocartilage","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is the major cation present in extra-cellular fluid (ECF)?","answers":[{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Iron","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is the most abundant anion in the intra-cellular fluid?","answers":[{"option":"Phosphate","bool":true},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Chloride","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphates","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A tissue is stained with hematoxylin and eosin (H&E) and it is readily stained blue. What does this signify about the tissue?","answers":[{"option":"Hydrophobic","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrophilic","bool":false},{"option":"Acidophilic","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrate rich","bool":false},{"option":"Basophilic","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"During the posttranscriptional modification of mRNA which of the following is added at the 3' end?","answers":[{"option":"Poly-U tail","bool":false},{"option":"Primer","bool":false},{"option":"7-methylguanosine","bool":false},{"option":"Poly-A tail","bool":true},{"option":"GTP-cap","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A chromosome has a protein conjugated with which of the following biomolecules?","answers":[{"option":"Nucleotides","bool":false},{"option":"Ribonucleic acid (RNA)","bool":false},{"option":"Histones","bool":false},{"option":"Deoxyribonucleic acid (DNA)","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleosides","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A boy fell down while cycling, injured his elbow, and started bleeding. Which of the following types of epithelium is damaged in this case?","answers":[{"option":"Simple squamous","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous non-keratinized","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudostratified","bool":false},{"option":"Stratified squamous keratinized","bool":true},{"option":"Simple cuboidal","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"While working in a warehouse a 45-year-old man is struck on the leg by a falling pallet rack. It strikes him on his left leg in the region of his thigh. The skin is not broken. Within 2 days there is a 5 x 7 cm purple color bruise at the site of injury. Which of the following substances has most likely accumulated at the site of injury to produce a yellow-brown color at the site of injury 16 days later?","answers":[{"option":"Melanin","bool":false},{"option":"Bilirubin","bool":true},{"option":"Hemosiderin","bool":false},{"option":"Lipofuscin","bool":false},{"option":"Glycogen","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A person raises their foot towards their knee with toes pointing upwards. What is this movement of the foot termed?","answers":[{"option":"Inversion","bool":false},{"option":"Dorsiflexion","bool":true},{"option":"Eversion","bool":false},{"option":"Plantarflexion","bool":false},{"option":"Extension","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following statements best describes reposition?","answers":[{"option":"A special kind of movement involving circular motion of the thumb","bool":false},{"option":"A movement in which the thumb and finger return to anatomical position after opposition","bool":true},{"option":"A movement involving flexion of arm","bool":false},{"option":"A movement in which thumb touches the tips of fingers","bool":false},{"option":"A movement involving flexion of wrist","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"What is the function of flagella in bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Acts as sex pilli","bool":false},{"option":"Locomotion","bool":true},{"option":"To obtain nutrient in agar medium","bool":false},{"option":"Reproduction","bool":false},{"option":"Adherence to tissue surface","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following types of RNA exhibits catalytic property?","answers":[{"option":"Ribonuclease","bool":false},{"option":"Ribosome","bool":false},{"option":"Ribonucleotide","bool":false},{"option":"mRNA","bool":false},{"option":"Ribozyme","bool":true}]},{"id":36,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The part of decidua which lies underneath the implanted embryo is termed as?","answers":[{"option":"Fused parietalis and basalis","bool":false},{"option":"Decidua basalis","bool":true},{"option":"Decidua parietalis","bool":false},{"option":"Decidua capsularis","bool":false},{"option":"Fused parietalis and capsularis","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A 48-year-old man who has a history of chronic alcohol abuse is capable of doing his work just fine. He has had no major illnesses and physical examination reveals no significant findings. Laboratory studies also do not show any significant dysfunction. Which of the following findings are likely to be seen in his liver under light microscope?","answers":[{"option":"Nuclear changes; karyolysis, pyknosis, karyorrhexis","bool":false},{"option":"Complete destruction of architecture of liver","bool":false},{"option":"Accumulation of large lipid droplets within hepatocytes","bool":true},{"option":"Detachment of polysomes","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertrophy of smooth endoplasmic reticulum","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Bacteria that are permanent residents in various parts of the body are known as normal flora. Which of the following statements best describes the colonization of the bacteria?","answers":[{"option":"Certain bacteria and fungi which are always present in mouth, colon and vagina","bool":false},{"option":"They are permanent residents","bool":false},{"option":"They provide essential vitamins","bool":false},{"option":"They inhibit pathogenic organism from binding to the epithelial surfaces","bool":false},{"option":"This is the acquisition of new organisms","bool":true}]},{"id":39,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The normal flora inhibits pathogenic bacteria from binding to the mucosal surfaces of the body. Which of the following statements best describes the mechanism of colonization resistance?","answers":[{"option":"Malnourished patients develop vitamin deficiencies due to reduced flora","bool":false},{"option":"Intestinal bacteria provide vitamins B and K","bool":false},{"option":"Normal flora causes disease in immunocompromised patients","bool":false},{"option":"The resident bacteria occupy attachment sites on the mucosa","bool":true},{"option":"Excessive use of antibiotics suppress normal flora","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The excessive use of antibiotics can have serious side effects on the body, especially the gastrointestinal tract (GIT). Which organism can lead to the formation of a pseudo-membrane in the GIT due to excessive antibiotic use?","answers":[{"option":"Escherichia coli","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococci","bool":false},{"option":"Clostridium difficile","bool":true},{"option":"Staphylococci","bool":false},{"option":"Balantidium coli","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The presence of a cluster of flagella on a single pole of a bacterial cell is termed?","answers":[{"option":"Bipolar flagella","bool":false},{"option":"Lophotrichous","bool":true},{"option":"Monotrichous","bool":false},{"option":"Petritrichous","bool":false},{"option":"Amphitrichous","bool":false}]},{"id":42,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following statements regarding somites is incorrect?","answers":[{"option":"Rate of formation is 3 per day","bool":false},{"option":"Forms axial skeleton","bool":false},{"option":"44-47 pairs of somites are formed in fetal life","bool":true},{"option":"Involved in age determination during fetal period","bool":false},{"option":"Blocks of paraxial mesoderm","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A high pKa value refers to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cation","bool":false},{"option":"Strong acid","bool":false},{"option":"Zwitter ion","bool":false},{"option":"Amphoteric ion","bool":false},{"option":"Weak acid","bool":true}]},{"id":44,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is incorrect regarding the periosteum?","answers":[{"option":"Has an outer layer of fibrous connective tissue","bool":false},{"option":"It contains osteoprogenitor cells","bool":false},{"option":"Contains osteoblasts","bool":false},{"option":"Contains type 1 collagen","bool":false},{"option":"It is avascular","bool":true}]},{"id":45,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following amino acids is not produced in the body and is therefore needed in our diet?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamine","bool":false},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false},{"option":"Alanine","bool":false},{"option":"Phenylalanine","bool":true},{"option":"Arginine","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the semi-conservative model of DNA replication?","answers":[{"option":"Fragments of both new and old strand are dispersed in daughter DNA","bool":false},{"option":"Parental strands stay together as new DNA is formed","bool":false},{"option":"Daughter DNA contains one strand of parental and one strand of new DNA","bool":true},{"option":"Two entirely new daughter DNA are formed","bool":false},{"option":"No new strand is formed","bool":false}]},{"id":47,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is a function of the sodium-potassium pump in the cell membrane?","answers":[{"option":"Decreasing heat production","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect transport of glucose into the cell","bool":false},{"option":"Synthesis of ATP","bool":false},{"option":"Increasing electropositive character inside the cell","bool":false},{"option":"Controlling cell volume","bool":true}]},{"id":48,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which type of chorionic villi is involved in the exchange of nutrients and wastes between maternal and fetal blood?","answers":[{"option":"Anchoring villi","bool":false},{"option":"Tertiary villi","bool":false},{"option":"Free terminal villi","bool":true},{"option":"Secondary villi","bool":false},{"option":"Primary villi","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Monosaccharides that are mirror images of each other are known as?","answers":[{"option":"Diastereoisomers","bool":false},{"option":"Isomers","bool":false},{"option":"Stereoisomers","bool":false},{"option":"Epimer","bool":false},{"option":"Enantiomers","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"An athlete was doing his third set of push-ups. What is his anatomical position in this situation?","answers":[{"option":"Recumbent","bool":false},{"option":"Prone","bool":true},{"option":"Supine","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral","bool":false},{"option":"Medial","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following parts of the nucleus is composed of histone proteins and DNA?","answers":[{"option":"Nuclear pore","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleolus","bool":false},{"option":"Nuclear envelope","bool":false},{"option":"Chromatin","bool":true},{"option":"Nucleoplasm","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The hormones epinephrine, norepinephrine, and thyroxine are derivatives of which of the following amino acids?","answers":[{"option":"Valine","bool":false},{"option":"Tryptophan","bool":false},{"option":"Ornithine","bool":false},{"option":"Tyrosine","bool":true},{"option":"Glycine","bool":false}]},{"id":53,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following cells is not derived from the neural crest cells?","answers":[{"option":"Odonocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Schwann cells","bool":false},{"option":"Melanocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Glial cells","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":true}]},{"id":54,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following biomolecules contain a polyhydroxy aldehyde or a polyhydroxy ketone in its structure?","answers":[{"option":"Proteins","bool":false},{"option":"Nucleic acids","bool":false},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Carbohydrates","bool":true},{"option":"Steroids","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A patient suffers some burns. The skin looks red with painful blisters. Which of the following layers of the skin are most likely to be affected?","answers":[{"option":"Epidermis and deep dermis","bool":false},{"option":"Only dermis","bool":false},{"option":"Epidermis","bool":false},{"option":"Epidermis and superficial dermis","bool":true},{"option":"Epidermis and the entire dermis","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The deficiency of which of the following lipids can result in respiratory distress syndrome in pre-term infants?","answers":[{"option":"Dipalmitoyl lecithin","bool":true},{"option":"Cephalin","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl inositol","bool":false},{"option":"Phosphatidyl serine","bool":false},{"option":"Sphingomyelin","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A 65-year-old man fainted and is brought to the emergency room. When he regains consciousness, he is unable to speak and has paralysis. The doctors diagnose him with cerebral artery occlusion resulting in ischemia of the left cerebral hemisphere. What type of necrosis has occurred in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Coagulative necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Fat necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Liquefactive necrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Gangrenous necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"In which of the following regions of the body the normal flora is absent?","answers":[{"option":"Throat","bool":false},{"option":"Small intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Large intestine","bool":false},{"option":"Blood","bool":true},{"option":"Skin","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A 16-year-old boy came to the hospital with the complaint of an inability to lift his leg. Muscle testing was performed and it revealed the weakening of his muscles. What is the weakened muscle called in this movement?","answers":[{"option":"Extensor","bool":false},{"option":"Flexor","bool":false},{"option":"Antagonist","bool":false},{"option":"Prime mover","bool":true},{"option":"Synergist","bool":false}]},{"id":60,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following carbohydrates modifies lipid absorption from the intestine?","answers":[{"option":"Alpha glucan","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Starch","bool":false},{"option":"Cellulose","bool":false},{"option":"Beta glucan","bool":true}]},{"id":61,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following bonds exists between the two monomers of a disaccharide?","answers":[{"option":"Glycosidic bond","bool":true},{"option":"Ionic bond","bool":false},{"option":"Ether bond","bool":false},{"option":"Ester bond","bool":false},{"option":"Peptide bond","bool":false}]},{"id":62,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following has the highest concentration of triacylglycerol (TAG)?","answers":[{"option":"Low density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Apolipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"High density lipoprotein","bool":false},{"option":"Very low density lipoproteins","bool":false},{"option":"Chylomicrons","bool":true}]},{"id":63,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is not a phase 1 reaction in the process of drug metabolism?","answers":[{"option":"Conjugation","bool":true},{"option":"Reduction","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidation","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydrogenation","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrolysis","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following are essential fatty acids?","answers":[{"option":"Palmitic acid and palmitoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid, alpha linoleic acid, and oleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Arachidonic acid and linoleic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Linoleic acid, alpha linoleic acid, and arachidonic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Acetic acid, butyric acid, and capric acid","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"What is the class of isomers that differ in structure because of the different arrangement of functional groups around the carbon atoms called?","answers":[{"option":"Optical isomers","bool":false},{"option":"Structural isomers","bool":true},{"option":"Chain isomers","bool":false},{"option":"Epimers","bool":false},{"option":"Enantiomers","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"The structure of the inhibitor is similar to the structure of the substrate in which of the following types of enzyme inhibition?","answers":[{"option":"Allosteric inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Irreversible inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Competitive inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Feedback inhibition","bool":false},{"option":"Non-competitive inhibition","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following terms is described as the point at which the net charge on an amino acid is neutral?","answers":[{"option":"Dissociation point","bool":false},{"option":"Solubility point","bool":false},{"option":"Isoelectric point","bool":true},{"option":"Ionization point","bool":false},{"option":"Neutral point","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Cleavage lines of the skin indicate the direction of orientation of which of the following fibers?","answers":[{"option":"Muscle fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Fibronectin fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Reticular fibers","bool":false},{"option":"Collagen fibers","bool":true},{"option":"Elastic fibers","bool":false}]},{"id":69,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following statements is correct regarding apoptosis?","answers":[{"option":"Apoptosis involves the inactivation of caspases","bool":false},{"option":"Intrinsic pathway is also known as death receptor pathway","bool":false},{"option":"BAX and BAK are pro-apoptotic proteins","bool":true},{"option":"Caspase 3 and 6 are initiator caspases","bool":false},{"option":"Extrinsic pathway is also known as the mitochondrial pathway","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A 10-year-old boy presents to the emergency department after an injury to his leg. Upon examination, it is observed that he is unable to extend his leg. The affected movement occurs in which of the following planes?","answers":[{"option":"Frontal plane","bool":false},{"option":"Sagittal plane","bool":true},{"option":"Median plane","bool":false},{"option":"Transverse plane","bool":false},{"option":"Coronal plane","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following carbohydrates serves as a stored form of energy in animals?","answers":[{"option":"Glycogen","bool":true},{"option":"Galactose","bool":false},{"option":"Glucose","bool":false},{"option":"Mannose","bool":false},{"option":"Sucrose","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following is the appropriate property of skeletal muscles?","answers":[{"option":"Involuntary muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Fusiform shape","bool":false},{"option":"Single nucleus","bool":false},{"option":"Gap junctions","bool":false},{"option":"Striated muscle","bool":true}]},{"id":73,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A patient is diagnosed with the dislocation of a synovial joint in the upper limb. Which of the following is an inappropriate statement regarding the synovial type of joints?","answers":[{"option":"They possess intra-capsular and extra-capsular ligaments","bool":false},{"option":"They are immobile","bool":true},{"option":"They have a synovial cavity","bool":false},{"option":"They have articulating hyaline cartilage","bool":false},{"option":"They have fibrous tissue","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Ammonia is converted into which of the following non-toxic amino acids?","answers":[{"option":"Glutamate","bool":false},{"option":"Aspargine","bool":false},{"option":"Histidine","bool":false},{"option":"Glutamine","bool":true},{"option":"Aspartate","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following solutions would cause red blood cells to shrink?","answers":[{"option":"0.1% NaCl","bool":false},{"option":"0.5% NaCl","bool":false},{"option":"0.3% NaCl","bool":false},{"option":"0.9% NaCl","bool":false},{"option":"1.0% NaCl","bool":true}]},{"id":76,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Gangliosides are complex sphingolipids mostly found in which of the following cells of the body?","answers":[{"option":"Oligodendrocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Neurons","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells of central nervous system","bool":true},{"option":"All cells of the body","bool":false},{"option":"Ganglion cells of peripheral nervous system","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following minerals is required to maintain the membrane potential?","answers":[{"option":"Sodium","bool":true},{"option":"Calcium","bool":false},{"option":"Fluorine","bool":false},{"option":"Magnesium","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorine","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following vitamins acts as a coenzyme?","answers":[{"option":"Vitamin D","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin E","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B12 only","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin A","bool":false},{"option":"Vitamin B complex","bool":true}]},{"id":79,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"A group of friends visited a cold hilly area during their winter vacations. Which of the following physiological responses is most likely to occur in their body?","answers":[{"option":"Shivering of skeletal muscles","bool":true},{"option":"Increased sweating","bool":false},{"option":"Vasodilation","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of piloerector muscles","bool":false},{"option":"Relaxation of skeletal muscles","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"Which of the following best explains why obligate anaerobes cannot grow in the presence of oxygen?","answers":[{"option":"They lack superoxide dismutase and catalase","bool":true},{"option":"They possess defences to make aerobic life possible","bool":false},{"option":"They require oxygen for ATP generation","bool":false},{"option":"They can not use the fermentation pathway for ATP generation","bool":false},{"option":"They need ATP produced by host cells for survival","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"1st-year/foundation/2022","question":"When preparing a tissue for routine light microscopic study, which procedure is carried out once the tissue proteins are fixed in a solution of fixatives and cross-linking compounds?","answers":[{"option":"Embedding","bool":false},{"option":"Cleaving","bool":false},{"option":"Dehydration","bool":true},{"option":"Fixation","bool":false},{"option":"Staining","bool":false}]}]
export default arr